Contact

7ramakant@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ramakantrana (LinkedIn) ramakantrana.com (Personal)

CrazyProf.in (Company)

Top Skills

Teaching

Research

Public Speaking

Certifications

Writing a persuasive cover letter for your manuscript

Presentation Design

Member

Life Member

Life member

Publications

Development of Hybrid EDM Electrode for Improving Surface Morphology

A Textbook of Engineering Drawing

Ramakant Rana

Co-Founder at Crazy Prof™ || Author || PhD Scholar || Assistant Professor || YouTuber || Wanna be Science Communicator Delhi

Summary

Experienced Assistant Professor with a demonstrated history of working in the education management industry. Skilled in Nonprofit Organizations, E-Learning, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, and Lecturing. Strong education professional with a Doctor of Philosophy PhD (Pursuing) focused in Production Engineering from Delhi Technological University.

Experience

Crazy Prof

Co-Founder

June 2017 - Present (3 years 3 months)

New Delhi Area, India

Maharaja Agrasen Institute of Technology 10 years

Assistant Professor

October 2014 - Present (5 years 11 months)

Delhi, India

Lecturer

September 2010 - September 2014 (4 years 1 month)

Delhi, India

YouTube (Ramakant Rana)

YouTube Presenter

October 2010 - Present (9 years 11 months)

Delhi, India

Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi Summer Fellowship Researcher June 2011 - July 2011 (2 months)

Delhi, India

Summer Fellowship Research Programme under TEQIP at IIT Delhi (SFRP-2011)

Role and Responsibility:

- Analysed Literature Reviews,
- Modified, tested, verified and analyzed research data,
- Learned to use Electron Microscopy (SEM).
- Learned various optimization techniques viz.
- Taguchi Optimization Technique, Response Surface Methodology, Genetic Algorithm, etc.

Education

Delhi Technological University (Formerly DCE)

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Production Engineering (2016 - 2020)

Delhi Technological University (Formerly DCE) M.Tech, Production Engineering · (2011 - 2014)

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University
Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Mechanical and Automation
Engineering · (2006 - 2010)